# MAURO DONEDA

London Area, UK | M: 07534 154055

| mauro.doneda@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/maurodoneda | github.com/maurodoneda

# **About**

I'm a Full Stack Software Developer with a background in Engineering and Finance. I'm passionate about coding and currently I can code in C#/.Net, HTML/CSS, JavaScript and SQL, all following OOP principles. I love to learn new things and my approach to life is: No challenge is too big. Each time you fall you get up stronger! I have a STEM degree: Masters in Mechanical Engineering, and a Masters degree in Financial Markets. My background comprises of 4 years of experience working for big Multinational companies in the heavy industry and 4 years as a Trader of the stock markets in a proprietary trading desk and independently.

- Check my personal website at <u>maurodoneda.com</u> and see some of my <u>Projects</u>

# **Personal Projects**

- *Movies Database WebApp* - An Interactive movie search webapp where you can query through any movie that you would like to watch, see its trailer and add to your own watchlist.

Tech used: HTML5 / CSS3 / JavaScript / Youtube API / JSON and AJAX

- **Supercar Experience WebApp** - A webapp that you can look details of supercars and select one of them to book a supercar experience in one of the cities available.

Tech used: .Net/ ASP.Net MVC-5 / C# /EntityFramework-6/ SQL-Server / Javascript / Bootstrap4 and

- *Chess Game* - A console chess game you can play using your keyboard. Built using Object Oriented Program paradigm.

Tech used: C# /.NetCore / OOP

# Skills

## **Technologies**

- C.#
- .Net Core
- HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript
- jQuery
- React
- MySQL and SQLServer

## **Tools and Methodologies**

- Visual Studio
- VS Code
- Command Line
- Git
- JSON
- SOLID
- Object Oriented Programing

## Soft Skills

- Empathy
- Proactivity
- Good Comunicator
- Grit
- Quick Learner
- Logical Thinking
- Team Oriented
- Creative

# **Experience**

#### **DEVELOPMENT PROFESSIONAL PROGRAMME**

Jan 2020 - Current

Self-Funded Program - Just It - London, UK

 Joined a self-funded presential course where I studied and used the latest tools and technologies for development together with a small group of learners.

- Used Visual Studio and Visual Studio Code to create front-end apps with HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript.
- Used coding best-practices with C# and .Net to create small console applications.
- Created Full-Stack apps using ASP.Net MVC, Entity Framework6 and MS SQL Server.

#### STOCKS AND FUTURES TRADER

Jan 2016 to Jan 2020

Self-Employed - Sao Paulo, Brazil

- Perform short term operations in the Brazilian stock market using Order Flow Analysis,
  Price Action, and Dow Theory in order to make a profit.
- Utilized Risk and Statistical analysis for options trading.
- Returned 385% in 2019 Net Profit on day trade strategies and 119% on Options strategies.

## FINANCIAL ANALYST

Jan 2013 to Jul 2014

Votorantim Metals - Sao Paulo, Brazil

- Created several reports focusing on working capital KPIs and Cash Flow improvements.
- Planned and executed financial Working Capital Committees with the company's VPs through 2013 and 2014.
- Helped the implementation of the first BI automated report alongside holding controllers.
- Delivered a marketing project as part of the implementation of the MES automated system in all factories, presented to the board of directors in the training academy.
- Reviewed and provided comments on the adequacy of documents and took necessary steps to cure any deficiencies.
- Prepared budgets, forecasts and financial reports for analysis.
- Monitored multiple databases to keep track of the company's working capital variations.

#### PRODUCT SUPORT ANALYST

Apr 2011 to Jan 2013

Volvo Group(Contractor) - Curitiba, Brazil

- Spare Parts catalogue creation for Volvo Truck and Buses
- Analyse 3D models in order to correctly indicate spare parts to truck dealers around Latin
- America Participate in 9 different projects of Trucks and Buses launching in 2011 and 2012

# **Education**

## Masters, Financial Markets

Mar 2012 to May 2014

FAE Business School – Curitiba, Brazil

- Related coursework: Macroeconomy, Stock Markets, Strategic Planning, Financial Math, Risk Analysis.

# Master of Engineering, Mechanical Engineering Federal University of Parana – Curitiba, Brazil

Aug 2005 to Aug 2011

rederat oniversity of Parana – Caritiba, Brazit

- Related coursework: Project Management, Programming, Calculus, Linear Algebra, Advanced Maths, Physics, Thermodynamics, Fluid Mechanics, Vibrations Theory, Materials, Metallurgy, Product Design and Development.

# Spoken Languages

Portuguese | English | Spanish | Italian

# Interests

Trading | Sports | Traveling | Cinema | Reading | Cooking